tripomatic.com 2017-03-15

# Privacy | Sygic Travel

## In short…

We value your privacy and only collect personal information that is essential to what we do. We handle all personal information with reasonable care and according to the European law. We use cookies on the website to identify you and enable seamless browsing experience. We use respectable third party analytic tools as well as ad and affiliate networks that may use cookies or collect other information as governed by their own privacy policies. 

## Scope

This privacy policy governs your use of the software applications Sygic Travel Trip Planner app, Sygic Travel website and Sygic Travel Destination Guides apps. These are further referred to as "Sygic Travel". For a complete list of applications governed by this privacy policy, consult <https://itunes.apple.com/us/artist/tripomatic-s.r.o./id519058036>, [https://play.google.com/store/apps/developer?id=Tripomatic&hl=en](https://play.google.com/store/apps/developer?id=Tripomatic&hl=en), <http://appworld.blackberry.com/webstore/vendor/84286/> and [http://travel.sygic.com](http://travel.sygic.com/). 

## User Provided Information

Sygic Travel enables users to sign up using Sygic Travel account and third party sign in. Sygic Travel collects basic user data, including, but not limited to, e-mail address and user name and a password, in case of signing up with Sygic Travel account. This information is used to: 

  * Authenticate user to enable multi device sync and cloud storage of user created content.
  * Personalize the content provided to the user.

Submitting your personal information is voluntary. Should you decide not to provide particular information, you may not be able to use all services Sygic Travel provides. 

Sygic Travel may use Facebook integration. If you allow Facebook application, the app may access all information provided by Facebook, including, but not limited to your name, your e-mail address, your friends list or your likes. Use of Facebook integration is on a voluntary basis. For details, consult Facebook Data Use Policy <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>. 

Sygic Travel may use Google Account or Google Plus integration. If you allow this integration, the app may access all information provided by Google, including, but not limited to your name and your e-mail address. Use of Google+ integration is on a voluntary basis. For details, consult Google Privacy Policy <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>. 

Sygic Travel enables users to plan trips. It is therefore essential to collect information related to travel, such as destination, dates and places that the user wants to visit. 

We also store support requests for the purpose of providing customer support. 

Your e-mail address is used to deliver important transactional e-mail and periodical newsletters. These may have form of commercial messages and may include promotions. You may opt out by following the link added to every e-mail or by contacting us at [team@travel.sygic.com](mailto:team@travel.sygic.com). 

## Automatically Collected Information

In addition, Sygic Travel may collect certain information automatically, including, but not limited to, the mobile device vendor and type, your operating system, the IP address of your mobile device, and information about the way you use Sygic Travel. 

## Location Data

Sygic Travel uses information about the precise location of your mobile device. This information is not transferred to nor collected on our servers, with the exception of explicit user actions, such as saving user's current location as a part of user's trip. 

If you do not want your location to be tracked, disable location tracking on your mobile device. Doing so will affect functionality of Sygic Travel. 

## Cookies

Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser (if you allow that). Cookies enable the sites' or service providers' systems to recognise your browser and capture and remember certain information. 

We use cookies to save your preferences, such as your preferred currency, timezone or language. We also use session cookies to be able to identify the user after sign in and to be able to save edited data correctly. 

We never use cookies to save or track personal information. If you do not want our website to save cookies on your computer, set up your browser accordingly, use your browser in an anonymous mode or use cookie-less browser. Most browsers can also be set up to disallow cookies from certain domains or ask every time a website tries to save a cookie. 

## Third party access to information obtained by Sygic Travel

Data is periodically transmitted to external services using their SDKs to help us improve Sygic Travel and our service. We will share your information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement. 

Mixpanel is used to help us understand how the apps are used and also to help us detect important events and send out push notifications or e-mail messages. Consult Mixpanel privacy policy for more information at <https://mixpanel.com/privacy/>. You can also [opt out](https://mixpanel.com/optout/) from Mixpanel data collection. 

Google Analytics is used to help us understand how the apps are used. Consult Google Analytics privacy policy for more information at <http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html>. 

Google AdSense is used to serve ads on Sygic Travel website. Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Privacy Policy for Google Ads and Advertising Services](http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/privacy-policy.html). 

Facebook Audience Network is used to serve ads in Sygic Travel mobile apps. Learn about facebook privacy policy and data collection at <https://www.facebook.com/policy.php>. 

UXCam helps us understand how the Sygic Travel mobile apps are used by recording the user behaviour anonymously. Learn more at [http://uxcam.com](http://uxcam.com/). 

Fabric by Twitter helps us collect and analyze crashes in Sygic Travel mobile apps. Learn more at [https://get.fabric.io](https://get.fabric.io/). 

Sygic Travel may use data and code from other vendors that may collect information governed by their own privacy policy. These vendors include, but are not limited to [booking.com](http://www.booking.com/), [rentalcars.com](http://www.rentalcars.com/), [city-discovery.com](http://www.city-discovery.com/), [viator.com](http://www.viator.com/), [getyourguide.com](http://www.getyourguide.com/). 

The Facebook custom audiences feature is used solely for ads targeting on Facebook. Facebook will not share the targeting data with any third parties or other advertisers. To learn more visit <https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms>

## Disclosure of Information

We may disclose User Provided and Automatically Collected Information: 

  * as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process;
  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request;
  * with our trusted services providers who work on our behalf, do not have an independent use of the information we disclose to them, and have agreed to adhere to the rules set forth in this privacy statement;
  * if Tripomatic s.r.o. is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets.

## Opt-out rights

You can stop all collection of information by Sygic Travel easily by uninstalling the applications or ceasing to use the website. You may use the standard uninstall processes as may be available as part of your mobile device or via the mobile application marketplace or network. You can also request to opt-out via email, at [team@travel.sygic.com](mailto:team@travel.sygic.com). 

## Data Retention Policy, Managing Your Information

We will retain User Provided data for as long as you use Sygic Travel and for a reasonable time thereafter. We will retain Automatically Collected information for up to 24 months and thereafter may store it in aggregate. If you would like us to delete User Provided Data that you have provided via Sygic Travel, please contact us at [team@travel.sygic.com](mailto:team@travel.sygic.com) and we will respond in a reasonable time. Please note that some or all of the User Provided Data may be required in order for Sygic Travel to function properly. 

## Children

We do not use Sygic Travel to knowingly solicit data from or market to children under the age of 18. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with information without their consent, he or she should contact us at [team@travel.sygic.com](mailto:team@travel.sygic.com). We will delete such information from our files within a reasonable time. 

## Security

We are concerned about safeguarding the confidentiality of your information. We provide physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect information we process and maintain. For example, we limit access to this information to authorized employees and contractors who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve Sygic Travel. Please be aware that, although we endeavor provide reasonable security for information we process and maintain, no security system can prevent all potential security breaches. 

## Password Security

All user passwords are stored as salted hashes, which is an industry practice to protect passwords in case of a security breach. Nonetheless, users should never use the same password for multiple sites. Sygic Travel does not see nor collect your Facebook or Google+ passwords. 

## User Data Privacy

All trips created by Sygic Travel that are synced to the server are given a public URL under which the trip can be accessed and read. This link URL is private to the user and hard to guess. Access to the URL is however not limited in order to allow users to share the trip. 

## Changes

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time for any reason. We will notify you of any changes to our Privacy Policy by posting the new Privacy Policy at <http://travel.sygic.com/lp/privacy/>. You are advised to consult this Privacy Policy regularly for any changes, as continued use is deemed approval of all changes. 

## Your Consent

By using Sygic Travel, you are consenting to our processing of your information as set forth in this Privacy Policy now and as amended by us. "Processing,” means using cookies on a computer/hand-held device or using or touching information in any way, including, but not limited to, collecting, storing, deleting, using, combining and disclosing information, all of which activities will take place in the EU. If you reside outside the EU your information will be transferred, processed and stored there under EU privacy standards. 

## Legislation

Sygic Travel treats all private information in compliance with Czech legislation, which is transposed from EU directives. More information can be found at [The Office for Personal Data Protection](http://www.uoou.cz/uoou.aspx?lang=en) website. 

## Contact us

If you have any questions regarding privacy while using Sygic Travel, or have questions about our practices, please contact us via email at [team@travel.sygic.com](mailto:team@travel.sygic.com) or contact us in writing: 

Tripomatic s.r.o.  
Za Parkem 631/14  
621 00 Brno  
Czech Republic / EU 

## Thanks to...

This privacy policy is based on an awesome template provided by docracy.com <https://www.docracy.com/6016/mobile-privacy-policy>

Last updated: April 27, 2016
